(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
創聖のアクエリオン
Lyrics: 岩里祐穂 Composition: 菅野よう子
Genesis of Aquarion
Lyrics: Yuho Iwasato Composition: Yoko Kanno
世界の始まりの日
On the day the world began
生命の樹の下で
Beneath the tree of life
くじらたちの声の
The voices of whales
遠い残響 二人で聞いた
Distant echoes we heard together
失くしたものすべて
Everything we've lost
愛したものすべて
Everything we've loved
この手に抱きしめて
I'll hold them close in these arms
現在は何処を 彷徨い行くの
Where am I wandering now?
答えの潜む 琥珀の太陽
The amber sun where answers hide
出会わなければ
If we had never met
殺戮の天使でいられた
I could have remained an angel of slaughter
不死なる瞬き持つ魂
A soul with an immortal blink
傷つかないで 僕の羽根
Don't be hurt, my wings
この気持ち知るため 生まれてきた
I was born to know this feeling
一万年と二千年前から
From twelve thousand years ago
愛してる
I love you
八千年過ぎた頃から
From the time eight thousand years passed
もっと恋しくなった
I started longing for you even more
一億と二千年あとも
Even one hundred million and two thousand years later
愛してる
I love you
君を知ったその日から
From the day I first knew you
僕の地獄に音楽は絶えない
Music has never ceased in my hell
世界が終わる前に
Before the world ends
生命が終わる前に
Before life ends
眠る嘆きほどいて
Unraveling the sleeping grief
君の香り 抱きしめたいよ
I want to embrace your scent
耳すませた海神の記憶
Memory of the sea god I listened closely to
失意にのまれ
Swallowed by despair
立ち尽くす麗しき月
The beautiful moon standing still
よみがえれ 永遠に涸れぬ光
Arise, the light that never withers forever
よみがえれ 永遠に 涸れぬ光
Awaken, oh eternal and unwithering light
汚されないで 君の夢
Don't let your dreams be defiled
祈り宿しながら 生まれてきた
I was born while harboring a prayer
一万年と二千年前から 愛してる
I've loved you for twelve thousand years
八千年過ぎた頃から もっと恋しくなった
I've loved you more since eight thousand years passed
一億と二千年あとも 愛してる
I'll love you even one hundred million and two thousand years from now
君を知ったその日から 僕の地獄に音楽は絶えない
Since the day I met you, music has never ceased in my hell
君が繰り返し 大人になって
You repeatedly grow into an adult
何度も 何度も 遠くへ行って
And go far away again and again
見守る僕が眠れない
Watching over you, I cannot sleep
僕がくしゃくしゃになったとしても
Even if I end up worn and tattered
君の名を歌うために
In order to sing your name
一万年と二千年前から 愛してる
I've loved you for twelve thousand years
八千年過ぎた頃から もっと恋しくなった
I've loved you more since eight thousand years passed
一億と二千年あとも 愛してる
I'll love you even one hundred million and two thousand years from now
君を知ったその日から
Since the day I met you
一万年と二千年前から 愛してる
I've loved you for twelve thousand years
八千年過ぎた頃から もっと恋しくなった
I've loved you more since eight thousand years passed
一億と二千年たっても 愛してる
I'll love you even after one hundred million and two thousand years
君を知ったその日から 僕の地獄に音楽は絶えない
Since the day I met you, music has never ceased in my hell
幸せを願っただけで
I only wished for happiness
私の目に見えたのは
But what my eyes saw was...
誰かの愛が違う
Someone's love is different
誰かの愛を殺す世界で
In a world where someone's love is killed
この手に握った黒金
This black iron I hold in my hand
あとどれだけ冷静でいられるのだろう
How much longer can I remain calm?
それとも私はもう
Or am I already...
狂ってるの？
Going mad?
わからない
I don't know
どんなに未来を描いて
No matter how I picture the future
望もうがいても届かない
No matter how I hope and struggle, I can't reach it
何が正しいだと言うの？
What is it you call "correct"?
誰が心まで裁くの？
Who will judge even the heart?
ねえ
Hey
命が消える 優しさのせいで
Lives vanish because of kindness
弱さが罪と言うなら答えて
If weakness is a sin, then answer me
私は誰を犠牲に生きて
Whom am I living by sacrificing?
銃口を向ける 間違わないように
I aim my gun so that I don't make a mistake
唇を噛む 滲んだ血の味は
The taste of blood from biting my lip
誰も同じ あなたと奥底知ってた
Everyone's the same, I knew that deep down with you
終わりのない 悲しみの行く先は
Where does this endless sorrow lead?
どんなに怒りを飲み込み
No matter how much I swallow my anger
消してもその火は燃え上がり
Even if I put it out, the fire flares up
見据えた眼差しの先は
What lies ahead of my fixed gaze
もう決してぶれたりしない
Will never waver again
響く乾いた銃声
A dry gunshot echoes
遠くで聞こえる 罵声と絶叫
Abuse and screams heard in the distance
正義を問いかける
Questioning justice
私と彼ら どちらが死ねばいい
Me or them, who should die?
守れるものは一つしかないから
Because there's only one thing I can protect
他人の痛みを描い 心と寄り添う
Imaging others' pain and drawing close to their hearts
人はこんなにも 美しいのに
Even though people are so beautiful...
理由を見つけ 憎しみ合うんだね
...they find reasons to hate one another.
生まれたことに 意味がなきゃいられないんだね
They can't bear not having a meaning for their existence.
ならこれが私の答えだから
If that's the case, then this is my answer.
命が冷える 優しさのせいで
Life turns cold because of kindness.
弱さが罪と言うなら 応えて
If weakness is a sin, then answer me.
私は誰を犠牲に生き
At the expense of whom do I live?
銃口を向けたあなたに見えるように
So that you, with your gun pointed, can see.
そして銃声が響く
And then, a gunshot rings out.
遠くで聞こえる 罵声と絶叫
Curses and screams can be heard from afar.
正義を問いかける
Questioning what justice is.
私は生きる あなたを犠牲に
I will live at your expense.
自らの手を汚すこと
Getting my own hands dirty...
怯えないで 私は当事者になる
...don't be afraid. I will become the person concerned.
今
Now.
HiRyS, it's IRyS from Hololive English!
Thank you very much for coming to my very first 3D birthday live, Hope to the Future!
Yay!
初めての、えっと、3Dバースデーライブへ来てくださりありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for coming to my first, uh, 3D birthday live.
今回はね、えっと、『Hope to the Future』というタイトルのライブになっています。
This time, uh, the live is titled "Hope to the Future."
This time my live is based on a sci-fi anime song theme.
If you've noticed, my first two songs were "Sousei no Aquarion" and "Tojisha"...
...both from sci-fi animes. Yes, let's go! Because sci-fi is my favorite anime genre.
今回のテーマはSFアニソンになっています。
The theme this time is sci-fi anime songs.
先ほどの2曲もね、SFアニソンになってるかなと思います。
I think the two previous songs were also sci-fi anime songs.
『創聖のアクエリオン』と『当事者』でした。
They were "Sousei no Aquarion" and "Tojisha."
And with this wonderful theme, we have this wonderful stage available.
Yes, that staff-san made for me. Thank you so much!
It is a sci-fi spaceship. We're in space.
Yes, this is an IRyS spaceship.
Thank you very much. It's so pretty!
とっても素敵なね、えっと、SFテーマの宇宙船、
We have this really lovely, uh, sci-fi themed spaceship...
宇宙船？うん、宇宙船みたいな感じのステージになっています。
...Spaceship? Yeah, it's a stage that feels like a spaceship.
And with this, I would like to say, please do tweet with the hashtag #IRySBDay...
...while you're watching this to post your comments...
...and what you think of this live during the stream. Yay!
今回のハッシュタグ #IRySBDay で、ぜひ、えっと、このライブに関しての感想などありましたら、
Please use the hashtag #IRySBDay to post your thoughts about this live...
ぜひ呟いてください。イェーイ！
...if you have any. Yay!
Alrighty then, I think we should start off strong with a wonderful guest medley!
では早速ね、ゲストメドレーに行きたいと思います！
So without further ado, let's move on to the guest medley!
では、レッツゴー！どうぞ！
Here we go! Please enjoy!
名前のない怪物
Monster Without a Name
Lyrics ・ Composition ryo(supercell)
震え、似てるわ
You're trembling, it looks like...
軋んだみたい
...you're creaking.
煉瓦の病棟で
In the brick ward...
うまく歌えなくて
...I couldn't sing well.
霧に煙る夜
A night clouded in mist...
浮かべ赤い月
...where the red moon floats.
ほら見て私を
Look at me.
目を逸らさないで
Don't look away.
黒い鉄格子のなかで
Behind the black iron bars...
私は生まれてきたんだ
...is where I was born.
悪意の代償を願い
Wishing for the price of malice...
望むがままにお前に
...just as you desired.
名前のない怪物
A Nameless Monster
壊して
Destroy it
壊される前に
Before you're destroyed
因果の代償 払い
Paying the price of karma
共に行こう
Let's go together
名前のない怪物
A nameless monster
耳鳴りがしてる
My ears are ringing
鉄格子もうるさくて
The iron bars are loud too
思い出せないの
I can't remember
あの日の旋律
The melody of that day
あのまま止まない
It won't stop like that
何も見えないの
I can't see anything
ほら見て こんなに
Look, it's grown...
大きくなったの
...this big
黒い雨 降らせ この空
Let black rain fall from this sky
私は 望まれないもの
I am something unwanted
ひび割れた ノイローゼ 愛す
Loving this cracked neurosis
どうぞ 私に 裁きを
Please, judge me
震え正義を消せない 傷抱きしめて
Embracing wounds of an unerased trembling justice
この身体を受け入れ
Accepting this body
共に行こう
Let's go together
名前のない怪物
A nameless monster
あー
Ah...
神は
God...
告げる
...announces
真の世界を
...the true world
黒い鉄格子の中で 私は生まれてきたんだ
I was born within black iron bars
悪意の代償 願う望むがままに お前に
I wish for the price of malice, just as you desire
さあ果たせ よ 正義を
Now, carry out your justice
壊して 壊される前に
Destroy it, before you're destroyed
因果の代償 払い 報いよ
Paying the price of karma and receiving reward
名もなき怪物
Nameless monster
黒い雨 降らせ この空
Let black rain fall from this sky
私は 望まれないもの
I am something unwanted
ひび割れた ノイローゼ 愛す
Loving this cracked neurosis
どうぞ 私に 裁きを
Please, judge me
震え正義を消せない 傷抱きしめて
Embracing wounds of an unerased trembling justice
この身体を受け入れ
Accepting this body
共に行こう
Let's go together
名前のない怪物
A nameless monster
太陽曰く燃えよカオス
The Sun Says: Burn, Chaos!
（うー！　にゃー！）太陽曰く燃えよカオス
(Woo! Nya!) The sun says: burn, chaos!
（うー！　にゃー！）世界はDark！
(Woo! Nya!) The world is Dark!
うー！ にゃー！ うー！ にゃー！ うー！ にゃー！
Woo! Nya! Woo! Nya! Woo! Nya!
（Let's にゃー！）
(Let's Nya!)
心 揺るる 異形の神々
Hearts tremble before strange gods
私もあなたも 怖がりなもの好き
Both you and I are curious cowards
形 綴る 異形と逃げれば
If we flee with these strange forms
私とあなたは 炎天下でデート
You and I will date under the scorching sun
た・の・し・い・ね
So much fun!
焼けるぞ 溶けるぞ
You'll burn! You'll melt!
（生き物じゃなーい！）
(Not a living thing!)
咽ぶ 酷（ひやひや） それでも好きです
Choking with chills, but I still like it
私がいちばん 欲しいのは内の世
What I want most is the world within
姿（ばやばや） それでは行きましょ
In this form, let's get going
私にいちばん 似合うのは不条理
What suits me best is absurdity
鏡には （だん・だん！） だれなの？
Who's in the mirror? (Bang bang!)
（うっつらなーい！）
(Not reflected!)
だれなんだ やだやだ
Who is it? No way, no way!
欲望は 言葉にしなくちゃ
Desires must be put into words
ほら 満ちちゃうし
Look, it's overflowing
太陽なんか 眩しくて
The sun is just too bright
闇のほうが 無限で
The darkness is infinite
太陽ばっか
Nothing but the sun
太陽なんか
Things like the sun
眩しくって
Are way too bright
闇のほうが素敵
Darkness is far lovelier
＼（・ω・）／Hey!
\(・ω・)/ Hey!
Chaos, Chaos,
I wanna Chaos!
燃えよ混沌 無敵です！
Burn on, chaos! It's invincible!
＼（・ω・）／Hey!
\(・ω・)/ Hey!
Chaos, Chaos,
Uu! Nya! Chaos!
燃えるような気持ち
This burning feeling
（にゃんで〜？）
(Why-nya?)
うー！
Uu!
にゃー！
Nya!
世界はDark!
The world is dark!
うー！
Uu!
にゃー！
Nya!
うー！
Uu!
にゃー！
Nya!
うー！
Uu!
にゃー！
Nya!
レッツにゃー！
Let's nya!
枕ボタボタ 夢母の神々
Pillows dripping, the gods of dream mothers
私とあなたと 目的は違うの
You and I have different goals
絆ムカムカ 無理やりされがち
Bonds are sickening, often being forced upon us
私があなたを 守るけどピンチ
I'll protect you, but we're in a pinch
おかしいな 逃げるぞわめくぞ
That's strange... I'll run, I'll scream
狙われてる
I'm being targeted
帳降り降り ここまで来ました
The curtain falls, I've come this far
私は黙って 敵たちを蹴散らす
I'll silently kick the enemies away
焔メラメラ 此所ではダメです
Flames flare up, it's no good here
私に黙って スカートは脱がないで
Don't take off your skirt without telling me
望むなら 全全全滅しましょうね
If you wish, let's total-total-totally annihilate them
願わくば 跡形も無くね
If possible, without leaving a trace
現在なんと 危険だった
Right now, how dangerous it was
光りもんをください
Please give me something shiny
現在なんと 危険だった
Right now, how dangerous it was
光りもんで刺激
Stimulate with something shiny
＼（・ω・）／Hey!
\(・ω・)/ Hey!
Madness, Madness,
You wanna Madness!
呼べば冒涜 過激です！
Call it, it's blasphemous! It's extreme!
＼（・ω・）／Hey!
\(・ω)./ Hey!
Madness, Madness,
Ennui Madness!
呼べばきっと おしまい
If you call, it'll surely be the end
ハイヨルコンタン ニャルラトホテプ
Creeping Chaos, Nyarlathotep
うー！
Uu!
にゃー！
Nya!
うー！
Uu!
にゃー！
Nya!
うー！
Uu!
にゃー！
Nya!
うー！
Uu!
にゃー！
Nya!
うー！
Uu!
にゃー！
Nya!
うー！
Uu!
にゃー！
Nya!
うー！
Uu!
にゃー！
Nya!
レッツにゃー！
Let's nya!
太陽なんか
Things like the sun
眩しくって
Are way too bright
闇のほうが無限です
Darkness is infinite
太陽ばっか
Nothing but the sun
眩しくって
It's way too bright
闇のほうが素敵
Darkness is far lovelier
＼（・ω・）／Hey!
\(・ω・)/ Hey!
Chaos, Chaos,
I wanna Chaos!
燃えよ混沌 無敵です！
Burn on, chaos! It's invincible!
＼（・ω・）／Hey!
\(・ω)./ Hey!
Chaos, Chaos,
Uu! Nya! Chaos!
燃えるような気持ち
This burning feeling
（にゃんで〜？）
(Why-nya?)
ハイヨルコンタン ニャルラトホテプ
Creeping Chaos, Nyarlathotep
聞こえていますか 僕の声が
Can you hear it? My voice.
大切な人は もういますか
Do you already have someone special?
遠いようで案外そばにいるよ
Though it feels far, I'm actually right by your side.
君には僕が見えないんだろうけど
Though you probably can't see me.
忘れないでなんて言えば 君は困るだろうから
Because if I said "don't forget me," it would probably trouble you.
忘れていいよなんて 最後まで強がった
So I bluffed until the end, saying "it's okay to forget."
気づいてほしいよって 今更伝えたら
If I told you now that I want you to notice me,
やっぱり困った顔して笑うかな
Would you still laugh with that troubled face?
今の日々を愛さないで
Don't love these present days,
そこには僕はいないんだよ
Because I am not there.
何気ないことが幸せだったって
That the mundane things were happiness...
当たり前でしょう
That's only natural, right?
もしも願い叶うのなら
If my wish could come true,
隣で笑ってくれるのなら
If you could laugh by my side...
愛を教えてくれた君と
With you, who taught me love,
もう一度会いたい
I want to meet once more.
歩き方も 話し方も
Your way of walking, your way of talking,
あの頃のままで変わらないね
They haven't changed since then.
愛を教えてくれた君へ
To You Who Taught Me Love
でもなんだかちょっと
But somehow, a little bit,
君の顔が
your face
大人びて見えて
looks more mature,
胸がキュッと痛むよ
and it makes my heart ache.
別れが来ること
If I had known from the start
初めから知っていたなら
that a farewell would come,
おはよう ありがとう
Good morning, thank you,
ごめんね おやすみを
sorry, and good night—
もっとちゃんと
I wonder if I could
言えていたかなって
have said them more properly.
後悔しているよ
I'm full of regrets.
伝えたい言葉で
I'm overflowing with
溢れてる
the words I want to convey.
今の君に
I want to try
触れてみたい
and touch the you right now.
この手で強く
I want to hold you
抱きしめたい
strongly with these hands.
君がいない
Even today, from this world
この世界から 今日も
where you are no longer here,
名前を呼ぶよ
I'll call out your name.
まぶた閉じれば
If I close my eyelids,
いつもそこに
those beloved days
愛しい日々が
are always there,
蘇るよ
being revived.
涙色濡れた
Even memories wet with
思い出さえも 切なく煌めく
the color of tears sparkle painfully.
空の色や
Even if the color of the sky
街の音が
or the sounds of the town change,
変わっても想いは
my feelings will remain
消えずに残ってゆくんだね
without ever disappearing.
だからせめて
So at least I want
この声が届いてほしいよ
this voice to reach you.
君へ
To you...
今の日々を
Please love the days
愛していて
you're living now.
そこには僕は
I won't be there,
いないけれど
but...
同じ時代を
please don't forget the fact
共に生きていたこと
that we lived in the same era
忘れないでいて
together.
もしも生まれ
If I'm born again,
変わるのなら
and if we can laugh together,
僕らが笑い合えるなら
I want to meet you once more,
愛を教えて
the one who taught me
くれた君とまた
what love is.
もう一度巡り会いたい
I want to cross paths with you again.
愛を教えてくれた君へ
To you who taught me love
ファティマ
Fatima
この世界は非現実
This world is unreal,
ただ
just
すり込まれたビジョン
an imprinted vision.
流転 演転
Flux and transition,
価値観 今
values, now
上書きする 変哲のない
overwriting a mediocre
宇宙
universe.
傲慢な神は
The arrogant god is
目に映らない
invisible to the eye,
拘束力で支配し続ける
continuing to rule with binding force.
ならば 僕は
In that case, I—
僕だけは
at least only I—
奇跡的で致命的な マイノリティでありたい
want to be a miraculous and fatal minority.
I can fly high!
あの瞬間 あの場面が
If that moment, that scene,
君にとって特別なら
is special to you,
過去は離れていくものなんかじゃなくて
the past isn't something that just drifts away.
傷付くことの痛みより
More than the pain of getting hurt,
大事な真相の
all the light of
全ての光が今 零を
the important truth now... zero.
この命という無限
This infinity called life
まだ 咲かくと灯し出す
Still shining as if to bloom
二律背反 パラドックスさえ
Antinomy, even a paradox
終わりのない 世界線で欺き
Deceived in an endless world line
感情の支配 既知の秩序は
Domination of emotions, the known order
常識さえ すり替えてゆく ならば
If even common sense is being replaced, then
僕の
Mine
僕だけの
Only mine
苦しみ その結果さえ
Even the result of that suffering
アルゴリズムのまま
Just as the algorithm says
I can fly!
愛の印 愛の言葉
Symbols of love, words of love
明確なる この記憶を
This memory that becomes clear
二度と彼方へ置き去りには
I will never leave it behind
しないから
there again
いつでもまだ 君のそばに
Always still by your side
隣り合わせ その量子が
Side by side, those quanta
もつれ合えば ゼロになる
If they become entangled, they become zero
There is no god
Wonderful new world
The place was busy twice
まだ知らない 新しい空
A new sky I don't know yet
世界線へつなぐのさ
I'll connect it to the world line
I can fly high!
あの瞬間 あの場面が
That moment, that scene
君にとって 特別なら
If it's special to you
過去は離れて 行くものなんか
The past is not something that goes away
じゃなくて
but...
傷つくことの 痛みより
More than the pain of being hurt
大事な真実 その全ての
The important truth, all of that
光が今 ゼロを編む
Light is now weaving zero
There is no god
Wonderful new world
握り締めたメッセージ
The message I held tight
That's rising hope!
Welcome to our special rising
Can you feel the survivor?
Here we go!
揺るがない世界 非常な現状
An unshakeable world, an extraordinary reality
続く壁は何重層?
How many layers are the continuing walls?
イメージ通りなんかじゃない
It's not at all as I imagined
静かに騒ぎ出した本能
Instincts that have quietly begun to stir
迷路みたい 行き止まりなんだ
Like a maze, it's a dead end
思考はディストーション
My thoughts are distorted
容赦ないね いつの間に
It's relentless, isn't it? Before I knew it
見失ったルート 暴れ出す
The lost route starts to go wild
Pay attention!
Hey, what is it?
Watch your step now!
常識なんか要らない
I don't need common sense
Are you serious?
No no no, don't worry
1, 2, 3
吹き返す心臓のリズム
The rhythm of the heart breathing back to life
視界まで 眩んでる
Even my vision is blurred
それでも 行かなくちゃ
Even so, I have to go
君が信じてる 僕を裏切る
To betray the me that you believe in
わけにいかない
I can't do that
強くクラクションが鳴る
A loud horn sounds
孤独なまま 時が経ったって
Even if time passes while I'm lonely
逃げること覚えたって
Even if I learned to run away
新しい今日が来ちゃうけど
A new today will come, but...
(I believe in myself, rising hope)
この願い例え魔法が無くたって
Even if there's no magic for this wish
叶えなきゃ誓った
I swore I'd make it come true
僕は君とまだ見たい未来あるんだよ
I still have a future I want to see with you
泣きそうでも
Even if I'm about to cry
悔しくても
Even if it's frustrating
止まって いられない
I can't stay still
握り締めたメッセージ
The message I held tight
That's rising hope!
I will go ahead!
止まる暇(の) ノンストップで
No time to stop, non-stop
ガンガン迫る 走る
Approaching hard, running
Where's the solution?
打ちのめされても 負けな...
Even if I'm beaten down, I won't lose...
Get up!
Come on!
Hurry up!
そんなそんな時間なら
If it's that kind of time
すぐさまゴミ箱
Right into the trash can
後悔なんて塵埃(じんあい)同然
Regret is just like dust and dirt
さっさと投げちゃっておけ
Throw it away quickly
欲張り遊ばせ
Let your greed play
是非も賛否も全部僕のもの
Right and wrong, pros and cons, they're all mine
飛ばせ心臓のアルゴリズム
Let the heart's algorithm fly
ほら 守りたいんだって
See, I want to protect it
僕の声が伝播した
My voice has propagated
異論 反論は許すけど
I'll allow objections and counter-arguments, but...
思いもよらない 日に輝く 出来事でしょう
It must be an event that shines on an unexpected day.
Whoa!
築き上げてきた 理想の世界 言わなくちゃ
The ideal world I've built up—I have to say it.
君がくれた思いの 全部を信じて
Believing in all the feelings you gave me.
行ける それが嘘か どうかなんて 分からなくてもいい
I can go, even if I don't know whether it's a lie or not.
誰かが示す 見本てなんだっけ 普通の愛てなんだっけ
What was that "example" someone showed me? What was "normal love" again?
僕は 今日も 僕に問いかけ
Today, once again, I ask myself.
追いかけ 旅路で手に入れるのは 変わらない真実
What I'll obtain at the end of my journey is the unchanging truth.
僕は要らない まだ見ぬ未来が あるから
I don't need it, because there's a future I haven't seen yet.
孤独なんて 消えてなくなって 逃げること嫌になって
Loneliness has vanished, and I've grown tired of running away.
新しい 今日を探すんだよ
I'll search for a new "today".
この願い例え魔法がなくたって 叶えなきゃ誓った
I swore to grant this wish, even without magic.
僕と君で作れる未来なら もう近い
If it's a future we create together, it's already close.
僕の右手 君の左手 そっとつないで
Gently joining my right hand with your left.
握ったメッセージ That's rising hope
The message I've gripped tight—That's rising hope!
離さないから That's rising hope
I'll never let go—That's rising hope!
I will believe it! Rising Hope!
Hey! Don't let it go!
Can you continue?
Alright, make my way!
Phew!
And I'm back!
HiRyS, it's IRyS!
Anyways...
How did you guys like Rising Hope?
It was amazing, right?
Or more like, how did you guys enjoy the full guest medley?
It was a whole medley!
I sang so many songs with so many of my wonderful JP senpais.
Once again, thank you so much to my JP senpais for accepting my invitation...
...and for singing with me.
And at the end, I really wanted to sing Rising Hope with everyone.
So I'm really glad I was able to do that. It was one of my dreams.
Thank you so much!
えっと、Rising Hope とあとゲストパート、いかがでしたでしょうか？
So, how did you like Rising Hope and the guest medley?
えっとね、大変あの、光栄なことに...
Um, I'm very honored that...
...JPの先輩にみんなと一緒に、いろんな曲を歌えて...
...I was able to sing various songs together with all my JP senpais...
...最後はね、あの豪華なキャストで Rising Hope 歌えて...
...and at the end, sing Rising Hope with that amazing cast...
...本当にそれがね、あの、一つ私の、何て言うの、目標というか願いだったので...
...since that was truly one of my goals, or should I say, wishes...
...その願いが叶えられてすごく嬉しいです。本当にありがとうございました！
...I'm so happy that wish was granted. Thank you all so much!
Phew! And I think we're at the halfway mark? Yeah!
And now that we're in the halfway mark, we're also at a different place.
ここはどこでしょうか？
Where could we be?
We are at the Seiso Church! Yay!
めちゃくちゃ清楚なチャー... チャーじゃない、教会にいます。
I'm at a super seiso chur... not chur, but church.
Look at these pretty stained glasses! It's so pretty.
What kind of seiso song is this seiso Nephilim going to sing?
I do not know. No, I do know! I do know, but...
I wonder, I wonder. I'm sure you guys are wondering.
この清楚な教会でね、この清楚なIRySは一体どんな曲を歌うんでしょうか？
In this seiso church, just what kind of song will this seiso IRyS sing?
とても楽しみですね。
It's very exciting, isn't it?
では、次の曲を聴いてください。
Now, please listen to the next song.
Please listen to my next song.
きらり一瞬の光
A momentary gleam of light
対極する存在達よ さあ
Oh, opposing existences, come now
土へ 未来へ 空へ
Toward the earth, toward the future, toward the sky
接近していく 罪だって
Approaching, even if it's a sin
わかっていく 罠だって
Realizing, even if it's a trap
本当なら 密かにあるべきだろう
In truth, it should probably exist in secret
絶望なんて
Despair and such
宿命(さだめ)なんて
Destiny and such
瞳開いて 潮騒聴かせて
Open your eyes and let me hear the sound of the tide
そっと抱え込んで
Gently holding it close
すっと通り過ぎて
Quickly passing by
裏切り 揺らぎ
Betrayal, wavering
Dead or alive and go!
どこに行けば...
Where should I go...
世界と君が
The world and you
命をやり直すために
In order to redo life
生きていた証を記憶に刻め
Carve the proof of having lived into memory
向かうは
Heading towards
DEAD OR ALIVE in god
痛い 痛い 痛い
It hurts, it hurts, it hurts
砕け散って
Shatter into pieces
くらい くらい くらい
Dark, dark, dark
君とソライロ
With you and the sky color
引き急いで
Hollowly rushing
模索して
Searching
真実に見放さないで
Don't abandon the truth
正常なんて壊していく
I'll keep destroying things like normalcy
ストレスの模様なんだろう
What is the pattern of stress?
せっかく風になっていく
Finally becoming the wind
せっかく心に気づいて花になる
Finally noticing the heart and becoming a flower
DEAD OR ALIVE in god
君と僕が諦めぬまま
As you and I don't give up
世界を巻き込んでいけ
Drag the world into it
どうやって先頭して
How to lead
鼓動の闇当て交わる
The darkness of the heartbeat intersects
DEAD OR ALIVE in god
輝く空は僕らの鏡
The shining sky is our mirror
今を映した明日
The tomorrow that reflected the present
DEAD OR ALIVE in god
どこに行けば
Where should I go
世界と君が命をやり直すために
So the world and you can redo life
DEAD OR ALIVE in god
生きていた証を記憶に刻め
Carve the proof of having lived into memory
抗っていく
Keep resisting
DEAD OR ALIVE in god
君と僕が諦めぬまま
As you and I don't give up
世界を巻き込んでいけ
Drag the world into it
どうやって先頭して
How to lead
鼓動の闇当て交わる
The darkness of the heartbeat intersects
DEAD OR ALIVE in god
君とどこにいる
Where are you?
痛い 痛い 痛い
It hurts, it hurts, it hurts
砕け散って
Shatter into pieces
くらい くらい くらい
Dark, dark, dark
君とソライロ
With you and the sky color
痛い 痛い
It hurts, it hurts
砕け散って
Shatter into pieces
くらい くらい くらい
Dark, dark, dark
君とソライロ
With you and the sky color
And that was DEAD OR ALIVE!
Yes, another beautiful song from the Fafner series.
Since I sang Shangri-La for my 3D showcase,
I wanted to sing another Fafner song, so I chose DEAD OR ALIVE.
How did you guys like that?
ファフナーのね、あのDEAD OR ALIVE歌わせていただきました。
I sang Fafner's "DEAD OR ALIVE."
前回のね、あの3Dのお披露目配信ではシャングリラ歌ったので、
In the previous 3D debut stream, I sang "Shangri-La,"
それに続けて今回はDEAD OR ALIVE歌わせていただきました。
so following that, I sang "DEAD OR ALIVE" this time.
ファフナー最高なんで、もし見てない方いましたら、見てください。
Fafner is the best, so if you haven't seen it, please watch it.
If you haven't watched Fafner yet, I highly recommend you do,
'cause the songs are amazing and the anime itself is great. Yes.
Ah, and now that we've sung DEAD OR ALIVE,
I think we are past the halfway line of this live.
And now that since that's the case,
I think it's about time we announce something big,
something that I think a lot of you guys were completely expecting
because it's, you know, it's the usual stuff.
では、えーと、告知タイムに行きましょうか。
Well, shall we move on to the announcement time?
みんながおそらく期待していたというか、まあいつものね、告知させていただきます。
I'll make the announcement that everyone was probably expecting, or rather, the usual one.
では、ドン！
Here it is!
IRyS Birthday Celebration 2024
Birthday Celebration 2024
Birthday Merch Complete Set
Merch!
I will be releasing my birthday merch this year!
As you can see, it is sci-fi themed just like the live! Yay!
In with IRyS in her gamer uniform outfit in space!
Yay! Isn't it pretty? It's from Piske-sensei! Yay!
今回はね、今回のライブに合わせてSFテーマのイラストになっています。
This time, to match the live, it's a sci-fi themed illustration.
では、詳細いきましょうか。Now let's go to the details! Yay!
Now let's go to the details! Yay!
"Hope To The Future" DeskMatRyS
(Large Rubber Mat)
First off, we have the "Hope To The Future" DeskMatRyS! Yay!
えっと、ラバーマット、ワイドデスクマットになっています。
Um, it's a rubber mat, a wide desk mat.
From the same art from Piske-sensei!
It is slightly larger or wider than my past birthday mat that I released a couple years ago.
So I think you'll definitely have a need for that. It is going to look very nice on your desk.
Yes, I highly recommend you get it.
今回のデスクマットはね、何年か前の誕生日にリリースしたデスクマットよりちょいと長くなっています。
This desk mat is a bit longer than the desk mat I released for my birthday a few years ago.
なので是非々々デスクに広げていただけると、多分このイラストとてもデスクの上で映えると思うんで是非ゲットしてください。
So please, please spread it out on your desk; I think this illustration will look great on your desk so please get it.
今回のイラスト自体はね、本当にSFなのでパソコン周りとか全然似合うんじゃないかなと思います。
The illustration itself is really sci-fi, so I think it'll look great around your PC and such.
Alrighty then, next merch. 次いきましょう。
Alrighty then, next merch. Let's move on.
The Gamer JacketRyS
(Jacket)
The Gamer JacketRyS! Yay! The hypothetical jacket is no longer hypothetical! Yay!
えっと、今回の衣装じゃない、ゲーマー衣装の再現のジャケットになっています！
Um, it's a jacket that's a reproduction of my gamer outfit!
えっと、今回はね再現と言っても色違いになっています。みんなが使いやすいような黒にさせていただきました。
Um, even though it's a reproduction, this time it's in a different color. I chose black so it's easier for everyone to use.
でもデザイン自体はお揃いのデザインになっています。
But the design itself is a matching design.
多分とってもかっこいいので、是非ゲットしてください。
I think it's very cool, so please get it.
And as I mentioned before, I think maybe in a past stream that I wanted to release a jacket, matching jacket. Yay!
It is in a different color, it is in black so that it'll be easier for all of you guys to wear.
But the design is going to be matching with my gamer outfit, so I think it'd be nice to be matching. Yay!
Please do get it, let's match together. Yeah.
今回のね、お揃いなので、是非アイリスとお揃いにしよう。お揃いにしよう。
It's matching this time, so let's match with IRyS. Let's match.
是非購入お願いします。ありがとうございます。
Please consider purchasing it. Thank you.
Alright, and then next up, we have more clothes. まだお洋服系のグッズありますよ。
Alright, and then next up, we have more clothes. There's still more clothes-type merch.
The GuyRyS Cap
We have the GuyRyS Cap! Woo!
Finally! I'm sure a lot of you guys wanted a GuyRyS cap for the longest time, ever since GuyRyS came to existence.
It is a white cap with the GuyRyS logo on it!
Yes, it has your face on it, and it is white because, you know, GuyRyS' cap has to be white.
It is going to look amazing with the jacket, so I think it'd be best to buy it as a set. Yes.
Please do get it. If you are an Aristocrat, you need the GuyRyS cap. Buy it! Buy it now! Yay!
今回のね、アイリスのファン層のガイリスの帽子になっています。帽子を再現しました。
This is a cap for the GuyRyS, IRyS' fan base. I've reproduced the cap.
帽子はね、ガイリスのキャラクターでも白い帽子被ってるんで、その白い帽子になっています。
As for the cap, since the GuyRyS character wears a white cap, it's that white cap.
それでガイリスの顔が写ってる帽子になっています。
It's a cap with GuyRyS' face on it.
あのね、ガイリス、アイリスのリスナーさんだったらこの帽子被んないとダメでしょ！
You know, if you're a GuyRyS, a listener of IRyS, you have to wear this cap!
購入してちょ！
Please buy it!
あとジャケットと、黒いジャケットと多分いい色のコントラストになると思うんで、是非一緒に買って一緒に着装してください。
Also, I think it'll make a nice color contrast with the black jacket, so please buy them together and wear them together.
Complete Set Purchase Bonus
If you buy the full set, we will have a bonus postcard! Yay!
As for the postcards this time, there will be a limited edition set...
And of course, if you can't get the limited edition set, there will be of course a normal set bonus as well, so no worries.
For the limited edition set, there will be the postcard with the IRyS hand-sign, hand-signed, I will sign them one by one.
Postcards! Yay! So if you want the hand-signed postcard, please do hurry and get it.
Yay! Buy it, buy it now! Yay!
And if you perhaps do not make it for the limited edition set, no worries, there's still the normal stamped IRyS postcard with the signature.
signature and a special message from me, yes.
えっと、今回のねセット特典のポストカードになっています。
These are the postcards that come as a bonus for the sets this time.
えっと、今回も、前回と同じく、えっと、限定数量限定バージョンと通常セットも両方ともあります。
This time, just like last time, we have both a limited quantity version and a regular set.
数量限定の方ではアイリスの、あの、直筆サインを一枚一枚大切に書かせていただきますんで、えっと、それ希望の方はぜひ早めにご購入をお願いします。
For the limited quantity version, I'll be hand-signing each one with care, so if you'd like one, please purchase it early.
えっと、通常セットもぜひあるんで、えっと、期間、期間限定じゃなくて、数量限定のがもしなくなった場合はぜひぜひ、通常限定もよろしくお願いします。
We also have the regular sets, so if the limited quantity ones sell out, please check out the regular ones.
通常限定じゃない、通常の方もよろしくお願いします。
Not regular limited, I mean regular! Please check them out.
そちらの方でもアイリスのね、あの多分、汚い字ではなく、綺麗なアイリスの、あの箔押し、サインとメッセージがついていますのでぜひそちらもゲットしてください。
Those will also have my stamped foil signature and message—not in messy handwriting, but in my neatest script—so please get those too!
イェーイ！
Yay!
And, whew, that was the merch announcement!
Yay! How do- how do you guys like the merch? I honestly really, really like the merch this time.
今回、えー、グッズどうでしたか？すごく今回のグッズすごく楽しみにっていうか、めちゃめちゃ出来いいんじゃないかなっていう風に思ってるんで、ぜひゲットしてください。
What did you think of the merch? I was really looking forward to it, and I think it turned out really well, so please go get it.
And, not just that, there's still one more announcement! まだね、もう一つ告知あります。
And, not just that, there's still one more announcement! I still have one more thing to share.
なんと！I will be having a members-only after-birthday stream! Right after this! Yay!
Believe it or not, I will be having a members-only after-birthday stream right after this! Yay!
It is a special stream to thank my members. I will be singing more songs there.
So if you want to hear more IRyS singing after the stream, do join my membership, Nephil-family!
And be there! And I hope you be there.
はい。えっと、今回は、なんと初めてのね、あの、誕生日記念配信の後の、えっと、メン限配信やります！
Yes. This time, believe it or not, I'll be doing my first members-only after-birthday stream!
そちらの方でもね、アイリス歌うんで、こちらの配信でね、えっと、「もうちょっとアイリスの曲、アイリスの歌聴きたいなー」っていう気分になった方はぜひぜひ、
I'll be singing there too, so if this stream leaves you feeling like you want to hear a bit more of my songs and singing, then...
アイリスのメンバーシップに加入していただくと、そのすぐあとに、えっと、メンバー限定配信のアクセスできるんで、ぜひ加入して見に来てくださいね！
...if you join IRyS's membership, you can access the members-only stream right after, so please join and come watch!
ふー、ではではでは。
Whew, now then...
Now that I have announced my merch, I think we're getting towards the last part, but there is still more singing obviously.
And since we're singing more songs, I think we need to move back to the arena, this very arena! Yeah!
えっと、まだ曲歌いますけど、そろそろ、あの、最後の方になってきましたんで、えっと、次の曲はね、えっと、またアリーナの方に戻りたいなーと思っています。
I'll still be singing songs, but we're getting near the end, so for the next song, I'd like to return to the arena.
では、いきましょう！Let's go!
So, let's go! Let's go!
花びら　散りゆく
Petals falling away
夢なら　果てなく
If it's a dream, it's endless
それなら　涙は
In that case, the tears...
何処へと還らん
To where shall they return?
仕組まれている
It is being contrived
終結さえも
Even the end
求め過ぎてた
I had sought too much
答えならば
For the answer
記号の中で
Within the symbols
泳ぎ疲れて
Tired of swimming
行き着く先は
The destination
ただの「仮初」
Is just a "temporary thing"
永いとき　はなれても
Even if separated for a long time
知っている　必ず呼び合う　絆を
I know the bonds that will surely call to each other
運命と呼ぶこと
Calling it destiny
抱いて　抱きしめても
Embracing, even if holding tight
抜け出せない　定められた境界から
I cannot escape from the determined boundary
溶けてなくなるほどの
To the point of melting away
進化へと　おかえりなさい
Welcome back to evolution
白い結晶が降りそそぐ街
The city where white crystals pour down
全ては包まれるだけ
Everything is just enveloped
誰が決めた訳でもない
No one decided this
夢へ　おかえりなさい
Welcome back to the dream
心のままに
Just as your heart desires
君の瞳に
In your eyes
映るその影
The shadow reflected
何を想って　何を見てる
What are you thinking? What are you seeing?
感じる事に
To feeling
信じる事に
To believing
委ねる事に
To yielding
ゆだねる事に臆病になる
Becoming afraid of surrendering
訪れる長い時 待っていた
I was waiting for the long time to come
微笑んで支えになりましょう
Let's smile and be a support
孤独で空に願うのなら
If you wish upon the sky in solitude
いつか繰り返す命の出口
The exit of life that repeats one day
さらにその先の道も
And the road even further beyond that
きっと出会えると信じて今を
Believing we'll surely meet, I'll face the present
おやすみなさい
Goodnight
赤い血潮が渦巻く波間
Between the waves where red blood swirls
寄せては返す営み
The cycle of coming and going
愛し 愛され 一つになるまで
Until we love and are loved as one
おやすみなさい
Goodnight
時は満ちるから
Because time will be fulfilled
長い時 離れても
Even if we're apart for a long time
知っている 必ず呼び合う
I know we'll surely call out to each other
絆を運命と呼ぶ事
Calling our bond destiny
抱いて 抱きしめても抜け出せない
Even if I hold you and embrace you, I can't escape
定められた境から
From the fixed boundary
溶けてなくなるほどの進化へと
Toward an evolution that melts away
おかえりなさい
Welcome home
白い結晶が降り注ぐ街
The town where white crystals pour down
全ては包まれるだけ
Everything is simply enveloped
誰が決めた訳でもない夢
A dream that no one decided on
おかえりなさい
Welcome home
心のままに
As your heart desires
Encore! Encore!
Eh? I just used up all my energy and broke into pieces, though.
どうしようかな？
What should I do?
しゃあないな...
Can't be helped...
I'll sing one last song for you guys.
Oh, and merch sales start at 10:05
and my membership-only part will start at 10:15. So don't miss it!
Now please listen to my last song for the stream, Garnet.
グラウンド駆けてくあなたの背中は
Your back as you run across the ground
空に浮かんだ雲よりも自由で
Is freer than the clouds floating in the sky
ノートに並んだ四角い文字さえ
Even the square characters lined up in my notebook
すべてを照らす光に見えた
Looked like light illuminating everything
好きという気持ちが分からなくて
Not understanding what it felt like to love
二度とは戻らないこの時間が
This time that will never return
その意味をあたしに教えてくれた
Taught me its meaning
あなたと過ごした日々をこの胸に焼き付けよう
I'll sear the days spent with you into my heart
思い出さなくても大丈夫なように
So that it's okay even if I don't remember them
いつか他の誰かを好きになったとしても
Even if I fall in love with someone else someday
...ああ
...Ah
ずっと
Always,
特別で
so special
大切で
and precious,
またこの季節が巡ってくる
this season comes around again.
初めて二人で話した放課後
That time after school when we first talked,
誰も知らない笑顔探していた
I was looking for a smile no one knew about.
遠くであなたのハシャいでる声に
Hearing your playful voice in the distance,
なぜだか胸が痛くなったの
my heart somehow started to ache.
変わってゆく事を怖がってたの
I was afraid of things changing.
ずっと友達のままでいれる気がした
I felt like we could stay friends forever.
終わってく物など無いと思った
I thought that nothing would ever end.
果てしない時間の中で あなたと出会えた事が
Meeting you in the midst of endless time
何よりもあたしを強くしてくれたね
has made me stronger than anything else.
夢中でかける明日に 辿り着いたとしても
Even if I reach the tomorrow I'm racing toward,
あなたは ずっと
you will always
特別で
be special
大切で
and precious,
またこの季節がやってくる
as this season comes around once more.
いつまでも忘れないと あなたが言ってくれた夏
The summer you told me you'd never forget...
時間が流れ 今頃あたしは 涙がこぼれてきた
Time has passed, and now, my tears are falling.
あなたと過ごした日々を この胸に焼き付けよう
I'll burn the days I spent with you into my heart,
思い出さなくても 大丈夫なように
so I'll be okay even if I don't remember.
いつか他の誰かを 好きになったとしても
Even if I fall in love with someone else someday,
あなたは ずっと
you will always
特別で
be special
大切で
and precious,
またこの季節が巡ってくる
as this season comes around again.
Thank you so much guys for coming
to my very first 3D birthday live!
I've always wanted to do this, so I'm super happy
that I was able to finally do this.
And thank you so much for all your support
and all the wonderful staff that were involved
in making this live possible
and making this amazing. Thank you so much.
えーと、たくさんみんな、
Um, thank you all so much
初めての3Dライブに来てくださりありがとうございます。
for coming to my very first 3D live.
えっと、みんなの応援のおかげ、
Um, thanks to everyone's support,
それと素敵なスタッフさんの、あの、努力のおかげで、
and the hard work of the wonderful staff,
とてもいいライブになったかなと思います。
I think it turned out to be a really great live.
本当にありがとうございました。
Thank you so very much.
そして、チャンネル登録者100万人も、
Also, for the 1 million subscribers,
本当にありがとうございます。みんなのおかげです。
thank you so much. It's all thanks to you.
And thank you so much for helping me reach
1 million subscribers today. I really appreciate it.
Thank you very much for coming.
Bye-RyS!
IRyS BIRTHDAY LIVE 2024 / HOPE TO THE FUTURE
IRyS BIRTHDAY LIVE 2024
HOPE TO THE FUTURE